Hey everyone, welcome. Today we're going to unlock a real superpower in your English.
みなさん、こんにちは。今日は英語の本当のスーパーパワーを解き放ちます。
It's a word you already use, but we're going to totally master it.
すでに使っている言葉ですが、完全にマスターします。
Ready to make your English sound awesome? Let's get right into it.
英語を素晴らしく聞かせる準備はいいですか？さあ、始めましょう。
Okay, let's kick things off with a super simple question.
まずはとてもシンプルな質問から始めましょう。
Why was she happy? I mean, think about it. We ask why all the time, right? Like,
彼女はなぜ幸せだったのでしょう？考えてみてください。私たちはいつも「なぜ」と尋ねますよね？
why is the sky blue? Or maybe more importantly, why is pizza so incredibly delicious?
例えば、空はなぜ青いのか？あるいは、ピザはなぜこんなに美味しいのか？
Why is all about finding the reason?
「なぜ」は理由を見つけることです。
And boom, here's the answer. She was happy. Because she passed the exam. See that word?
そして、答えはこうです。彼女は幸せだった。試験に合格したからです。この言葉、見えますか？
Because? That's our magic key for today. It's like a bridge, you know? It connects the result,
「なぜ？」これが今日の魔法の鍵です。結果と理由をつなぐ橋のようなものです。
she's happy, with the reason she passed her exam. So let's officially introduce the star of our show,
彼女は幸せだった、という結果と、試験に合格した理由をつなげます。では、今日の主役を紹介します。
the word because. Its job is super, super simple. It just explains the reason why. For my friends
それは「because」という言葉です。役割はとてもシンプルです。理由を説明するだけです。
who speak Japanese, it's a lot like using say or none of that. Honestly, it's one of the
日本語を話す友達には、「say」や「none of that」に似ています。本当に、これは
the most powerful tools you have for explaining, well, pretty much anything.
ほぼすべてを説明するための最も強力なツールの一つです。
All right, so how do we actually use this superpower?
さて、このスーパーパワーをどう使うのでしょうか？
Let's start with the basic formula.
基本的な公式から始めましょう。
Think of this as level one, your first most important step to becoming a total pro at
これをレベル1と考えて、完全なプロになるための最初の重要なステップです。
explaining why.
「なぜ」を説明するための。
And hey, this formula is so easy to remember, it just goes like this.
この公式はとても覚えやすいです。こうなります。
First you give the result, then you drop in our magic word because, and finally
まず結果を言い、次に魔法の言葉「because」を入れ、最後に理由を述べます。
you give the reason.
結果 because 理由。簡単ですよね？
result because reason. Easy peasy right? Let's see this thing in action. Check out
これを実際に見てみましょう。この文を見てください。彼女は笑った、なぜなら彼のジョークが面白かったからです。
this sentence. She smiled because his joke was funny. Do you see the formula? The
公式が見えますか？結果は彼女は笑った。なぜ彼女は笑ったのか？理由は彼のジョークが面白かったからです。
result? She smiled. And why did she smile? The reason is his joke was funny. And
そして、それをつなげる小さな橋は？そう、becauseです！毎回うまくいきます。
what's that little bridge holding it all together? You guessed it, because! Works
さて、レベル1は完全にマスターしました。プロの技に挑戦する準備はいいですか？
like a charm every time. Okay, you've totally nailed level one. So are you
あなたはできるはずです。スキルをレベルアップさせて、この全体をひっくり返しましょう。
ready for the pro move? I know you are. Let's level up your skills and flip this whole thing
こちらを見てください。左側が標準的な方法です。
right on its head.
右側がプロの技です。彼のジョークが面白かったので、彼女は笑った。
So check this out. We've got the two styles side by side. On the left, our standard way.
何をしたか分かりますか？理由を最初に持ってきました。これが英語をもっと面白く、バラエティ豊かにする素晴らしいテクニックです。
But look over on the right at the pro move. Because his joke was funny, she smiled. See
でも、これは大事なことです。素晴らしいプロの技を使うとき、守らなければならない重要なルールがあります。
what we did there? We just put the reason first. This is such a cool trick to make
文の最初の言葉がbecauseの場合、特別な小さな友達を入れる必要があります。
your English sound more interesting and varied. But, and this is a big but. When you
それは、カンマです。
use this awesome pro move, there's one really, really important rule you've got to follow.
理由の部分の後にカンマを置かなければなりません。
When, because, is the very first word in your sentence, well, you need to bring in a special
だから、because his joke was funny, カンマ、彼女は笑った、となります。
little friend. And here it is, our special friend is the comma.
この小さな記号は、あなたの文を完璧にするための強力な友達です。
You have to put a comma right after the reason part.
でも、絶対に忘れないでください！
So it's because his joke was funny, comma, she smiled.
さて、動きは分かりましたね。ルールも学びました。さあ、ゲームの時間です。
This tiny little mark is a super powerful friend that makes your sentence sound perfect.
新しいスーパーパワーを試すための簡単なチャレンジをしましょう。
But whatever you do, don't forget it!
心配しないで、楽しいですよ、約束します！
Alright, you know the moves, you've learned the rules, now it's game time.
さて、最初のチャレンジです。
Let's do a quick challenge so you can test out your new superpower.
日本語は「雨がひょっていたので私は家にいた」です。
And don't worry, this is going to be fun, I promise!
あなたのミッションは、これらの英単語を並べ替えて正しい文を作ることです。
Okay, here's your first challenge.
さあ、少し考えてみてください。どうでしたか？
The Japanese is 雨がひょっていたので私は家にいた.
できましたか？答えは「I stayed home because it was raining」です。
Your mission is to unscramble those English words and build the right sentence.
これが私たちのクラシックな公式ですね？結果 because 理由。分かりますか？
Go ahead, take a second to think about it. How'd you do?
完全にコツをつかんでいますね。素晴らしい仕事です。
Did you get it? The answer is, I stayed home because it was raining.
次のラウンドの準備はいいですか？やりましょう！「試験に浮かったので彼女は幸せだった」。
That's our classic formula, right? Result because reason. See?
さて、これらの言葉をどう組み合わせますか？よく見てください。
You're totally getting the hang of this. Awesome job.
はい、それです。彼女は試験に合格したので幸せだった。
Ready for round two? Let's do it! 試験に浮かったので 彼女は幸せだった。
ちょっと待ってください。それは私たちの説明の最初の文と同じです。
Okay, how would you put these words together? Take a good look.
あなたはすでに基本的な公式のプロになりつつありますね。
Yes, that's it. She was happy because she passed the exam.
素晴らしい！さて、もう少し難しいものに挑戦しましょう。
Hey, wait a second.
よく見てください。この文はbecauseで始まります。
That's the same sentence from the beginning of our explainer.
そう、これが私たちのプロの技です。日本語は「寝むかったので彼女は早く寝た」です。
Look at you! You're already becoming a pro with the basic formula.
これらの言葉をどう並べ替えますか？
That is fantastic! Alright, I think it's time for a trickier one.
そして、私たちの小さな強力な友達を忘れないでください。素晴らしい仕事です！
Take a close look. This one starts with because.
正しい答えは「because she was sleepy, she went to bed early」です。
And look right there. You see it?
ほら、そこに見える？
little comma friend right after Sleepy. That is a perfect pro-level sentence. You are doing
「Sleepy」の後に小さなコンマがあるね。 これは完璧なプロレベルの文だよ。
so great.
素晴らしいよ。
Okay, here we go. The final challenge. You are so ready for this.
さあ、最後の挑戦だ。 君はこれに挑む準備ができている。
Hiduchu shoku wo tabenakatta no de karewa harapeko datta.
「昼食を食べなかったので、彼はお腹が空いていた。」
Yep, this one also kicks off with because. Give it your best shot. You can do this.
そう、これも「because」で始まるよ。 全力を尽くしてみて。君ならできる。
Perfect. The answer is, because he didn't eat lunch, he was hungry. You did it. You
完璧。答えは「昼食を食べなかったので、彼はお腹が空いていた」だ。 君はやったね。
totally crushed both the basic formula and the pro move. And hey, even if you
基本のパターンもプロの技も完全にこなした。 たとえ少しつまずいても、それは全然問題ないよ。
stumbled a little bit, that is totally okay. Every single mistake is just a part of learning.
すべての間違いは学びの一部だから。 本当に素晴らしい仕事だ。
Seriously, great work.
本当に、素晴らしいよ。
So now that you're basically a master of because, let's add a few more tools to your toolkit.
これで君は「because」の達人だね。 次はツールをいくつか追加しよう。
See, because isn't flying solo. It's part of an amazing team of words called conjunctions.
「because」は単独ではなく、 接続詞という素晴らしい言葉のチームの一部なんだ。
So check out this chart. You can see because in some of its teammates. You've got when,
このチャートを見てみて。 「because」とその仲間たちが見えるよ。
which connects ideas about time, you've got if, which connects ideas about conditions.
「when」は時間に関するアイデアをつなぎ、 「if」は条件に関するアイデアをつなぐ。
They all work in a really similar way. And you know what the coolest part is? That
彼らはとても似たように機能するんだ。 そして、最もクールな部分は、
pro move with the comma, it works for these guys too.
コンマを使ったプロの技は、 彼らにも通用するということ。
And just like that, mission complete.
こうして、ミッション完了。
You came here to learn, and now you are officially an explainer.
君は学ぶためにここに来て、 今や公式に説明者だ。
You seriously have the superpower to connect results and reasons, just like a native speaker.
君は結果と理由をつなぐ スーパーパワーを持っているんだ、まるでネイティブスピーカーのように。
How cool is that? So let's do a super fast recap of your new power.
それはすごいことだね。 では、新しい力を超速で振り返ってみよう。
Number one, because tells us the reason why.
まず一つ目、「because」は理由を教えてくれる。
Number two, we've got two main patterns, result because reason, and the pro move
二つ目、二つの主要なパターンがある。 「結果 because 理由」と、プロの技「because 理由 結果」。
because reason result. And number three, the golden rule.
三つ目は、黄金のルール。
For that second pattern, you can never forget the comma.
その二つ目のパターンでは、 コンマを忘れないこと。
You have done such an amazing job today for real.
今日は本当に素晴らしい仕事をしたね。
You now have this incredible superpower to explain literally anything.
君は文字通り何でも説明できる 素晴らしいスーパーパワーを手に入れた。
So my final question for you is this, what's the first thing you're going to explain?
最後の質問だ。 最初に何を説明するつもり？
Go out there and use your new power. You've totally got this.
外に出て新しい力を使ってみて。 君なら絶対にできるよ。
Thanks so much for hanging out with me today.
今日は一緒にいてくれてありがとう。